Edwin Way Teale Papers 1981.0009
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series VII: Scrapbooks, undated, 1914-1979
  - 3 of 3: Scrapbook of Photography, undated (Box 233:, Folder 5409)
  - Part of scrapbook featuring Dr. Frank Crane's editorials, undated (Box 233:, Folder 5410)
  - 1 of 2: "Honors and Articles" scrapbook, 1970-1974 (Box 234:, Folder 5411)
  - 2 of 2: "Honors and Articles" scrapbook, 1970-1974 (Box 234:, Folder 5412)
  - 1 of 3: "Honors and Articles" -Earlham doctor of letters, etc., 1957 + (Box 234:, Folder 5413)
  - 2 of 3: "Honors and Articles" - The Garden Club.... etc., 1965 (Box 234:, Folder 5414)
  - 3 of 3: "Honors and Articles" -Dodd Mead's 25th anniversary..., 1962 (Box 234:, Folder 5415)
  - Birds in the news scrapbook, undated (Box 235:, Folder 5416)
    - 1 of 2: Scrapbook possibly meant as a "Biography of a Book" for his autobiography, 1979 (Box 235:, Folder 5417)
    - 2 of 2: Scrapbook possibly meant as a "Biography of a Book" for his autobiography, 1979 (Box 235:, Folder 5418)
    - 1 of 3: Scrapbook, 1923-1930s (Box 236:, Folder 5419-5421)
    - Earlham College Scrapbook, 1919-1923 (Box 237-238)
- Series VIII: Artifacts and Samples, undated, 1950-1978
  - Bone of Great Auk, undated (Box 239:, Folder 5422)
  - Clock used on Autumn Trip, undated (Box 239:, Folder 5423)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn Trip, undated (Box 239:, Folder 5424)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn Trip, undated (Box 239:, Folder 5425)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn Trip, undated (Box 239:, Folder 5426)
  - U.S. Army Button, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5427)
  - Fossilized leaf, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5428)
  - Rock samples "Cape May Diamonds", 1952 (Box 240:, Folder 5429)
  - Stomach stone from dinosaur, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5430)
  - Petrified dinosaur bone, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5431)
  - Petrified wood sample, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5432)
  - Petrified wood sample, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5433)
  - Rock samples, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5434)
  - Rock sample, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5435)
  - Insects in amber, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5436)
  - Petrified Oyster Shells, undated (Box 240:, Folder 5437)
  - "Lucky Shells" from the beach at John O' Groats, undated (Box 241:, Folder 5438)
  - Gurnes Graves, 1966 May 28 (Box 241:, Folder 5439)
  - Aryshire Coast Pebble, Hudson Grave- Scotch Pine Twig, undated (Box 241:, Folder 5440)
  - Geological samples from Rockbourne, England, undated (Box 241:, Folder 5441)
  - Bones of the extinct Auk from Funk Island, undated (Box 241:, Folder 5442)
  - Pine cone from salt pine, undated (Box 241:, Folder 5443)
  - Shell "John O' Groats", undated (Box 241:, Folder 5444)
  - Flint "Savenahl", undated (Box 241:, Folder 5445)
  - 4 Feathers, undated (Box 241:, Folder 5446)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5447)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5448)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5449)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5450)
  - Twigs & nuts from Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5451)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5452)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5453)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5454)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5455)
  - Shells -Silver Strand, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5456)
  - Plant Pods with Berries, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5457)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5458)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5459)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5460)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5461)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5462)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 242:, Folder 5463)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 243:, Folder 5464)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 243:, Folder 5465)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 243:, Folder 5466)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 243:, Folder 5467)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 243:, Folder 5468)
  - Rock Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 243:, Folder 5469)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 243:, Folder 5470)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 244:, Folder 5471)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 244:, Folder 5472)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 244:, Folder 5473)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 244:, Folder 5474)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 244:, Folder 5475)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 244:, Folder 5476)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 244:, Folder 5477)
  - Geological Samples- Autumn trip, undated (Box 244:, Folder 5478)
  - Rock sample, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5479)
  - Thoreau bricks, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5480)
  - Elderberry sample- from Mrs. Leslie O. Anderson, Concord, MA, 1978 October 23 (Box 245:, Folder 5481)
  - John Burrough's trap door sample, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5482)
  - Thoreau Brick fragment, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5483)
  - Machine gun shell, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5484)
  - 2 Cat whiskers, 1950 (Box 245:, Folder 5485)
  - Thoreau booklet, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5486)
  - Thoreau pencil, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5487)
  - Brick from Fire House at Harper's Ferry, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5488)
  - A Conscious Stillness-, undated; 2 leaves (Box 245:, Folder 5489)
  - A Naturalist Buys an Old Farm- clippings from hot air balloon, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5490)
  - A Naturalist Buys an Old Farm- clay, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5491)
  - Springtime in Britain- wool sample, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5492)
  - Wandering Through Winter- EWT's pen, box of chewing gum, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5493)
  - Wandering Through Winter- Geological samples, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5494)
  - Wandering Through Winter- Geological samples, undated (Box 245:, Folder 5495)
- Series IX: Camera Equipment & Media, undated, 1958-1989
  - Cameras and Accessories Belonging to EWT, undated (Box 246)
  - Cameras and Accessories Belonging to EWT, undated (Box 246B)
  - Camera Accessories Belonging to EWT, undated (Box 247)
  - Plate Block of EWT, undated (Box 247:, Folder 2469)
  - Camera in Case, undated (Box 248, Folder data_value_missing_75b19c46d7ddb7e13f547beeb54e7813)
  - 3 8inch IBM diskettes of manuscript - A Conscious Stillness (?), undated (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_b0a67a1735169b6eb169f3e87a4cc105)
  - 5″ reel WOR Radio Martha Deane Program with EWT as guest, 1970 September 11 (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_2cc20d8b3ce29e9a5f8e76d64a4ce803)
  - 5″ reel Concord Year Sounds, undated (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_038ed30358ee44651f97d928b72d7f67)
  - 8″ reel tape of Thoreau Society Meeting, 1958 July 12 (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_97e1710f20a2094e371880146ef52bb0)
  - Cassette tape "A Walk At Trail Wood With Edwin Way Teale", 1978 November 20 (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_74efb73e6ecde6925e71569d3b08a8a7)
  - Cassette tape "Connie Hagar, EWT & NDT", undated (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_3331b7830393641cfdbf27dbe7fab2ce)
  - Cassette tape Tom Creswell "Edwin Way Teale", 1983 July (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_c34d4e838ac4ece58a6c042348bbcf66)
  - Cassette tape "Edwin Way Teale, Rockport, Texas", undated (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_51287eac99b2e2706b43731d957b4a67)
  - Cassette tape "Trail Wood to Mrytle Beach, SC to Rockport, TX", undated (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_2465755542fdc04604daae81787ad851)
  - Video tape: Natchaug Ornithological Society Christmas Count, 1989 (Box 249, Folder data_value_missing_b7223b3773a78f7a1aa5ac9e86470f35)
  - LPs (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_9d97c8c942270c37b7550a7630386e3f)
    - The Reader's Almanac, 1960 November 15 (Other LP, Folder 1165)
    - Excerpt from The Big Country, (1958) (Other LP, Folder 1166)
    - "Martha Deane Show", 1959 December 1 (Other LP, Folder 1167)
    - Reader's Almanac, 1956 December 11 (Other LP, Folder 1168)
    - "Martha Deane Show", 1956 December 27 (Other LP, Folder 1169)
    - Dune Boy Talking Book, undated (Other LP, Folder 1170a)
    - Dune Boy Talking Book, undated (Other LP, Folder 1170b)
    - Dune Boy Talking Book, undated (Other LP, Folder 1170c)
    - Dune Boy Talking Book, undated (Other LP, Folder 1170)
    - Dune Boy Talking Book, undated (Other LP, Folder 1170e)
    - Dune Boy Talking Book, undated (Other LP, Folder 1170)
    - Dune Boy Talking Book, undated (Other LP, Folder 1170g)
    - Dune Boy Talking Book, undated (Other LP, Folder 1170h)
  - Films (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_e104fb826eab9ea69118e59f7e324e6d)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 1 Grassroot Jungle, color kodacrome film, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_93e7e4c6e4c53fbbc7c993161d8d7c8a)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 2 The Tales of the Luna Moth, color kodacrome film, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_b27960e359be58ac0a77c22f9258c144)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 3 Insects, Long Island Producers, color kodacrome, warped, [1930s] (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_516a97f205645c361d186235967b70b1)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 4 Butterfly Botanist, Cornets Producers, black-and-white kodacrome, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_746c3db8088f31e38c2d0026f289154e)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 5 Insects, color kodacrome, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_ce6296a748accaa015e624729590fe33)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 6 Untitled, color kodacrome, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_e8764bf0929778757c8f03d0b4919850)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 7 Untitled, color kodacrome (second film spliced to end looks like Insect film [1943], [late 1930s] (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_780ab95c8b2d5d1d00c71ee4a73cfff3)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 8 Untilted, color kodacrome, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_512406a362dab8b072480f537c91cb8c)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 9 Untilted, color kodacrome, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_4d2653935a1f26f571e90cf24b44dccb)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 10 Untilted, color kodacrome, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_3aff5c7a3b7b8db0069b84f966d4ae26)
    - Accession 1981-0009.mp 11 Untilted, color kodacrome, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_55b172336a4d2f5e23a2f687ff3506f8)
- Series X: Memorabilia, undated, circa 1801-1990s
  - Calendar- American Museum of Natural History, photo by EWT, 1949 (Box 250:, Folder 5497)
  - Calendars- with photos by EWT, 1981, 1982 (Box 250:, Folder 5498)
  - Calendar with notes by Teales, 1972 (Box 250:, Folder 5499)
  - Worcester & Middlesex County, Massachusetts Maps, 1974 (Box 250:, Folder 5500)
  - Evolution of the species, undated (Box 250:, Folder 5501)
  - Boston Atlas, undated (Box 250:, Folder 5502)
  - Road Atlases with notes by Teales, undated (Box 250:, Folder 5503)
  - Miscellaneous Maps with markings by Teales, undated (Box 250:, Folder 5504)
  - Concord, Massachusetts maps, 1800s-1900s (Box 250:, Folder 5505)
  - Massachusetts area maps (Sudbury River, etc.) with notes by Teales, undated (Box 250:, Folder 5506)
  - 3 College related medals, 1 button, 1 Olney Police Badge, 1918-1924, undated (Box 251:, Folder 5507)
  - EWT's key to back door- Baldwin, NY (?), undated (Box 251:, Folder 5508)
  - EWT's pen, 1930-1965 (Box 251:, Folder 5509)
  - Cufflinks presented to EWT from Joliet Township Highschool, 1955 (Box 251:, Folder 5510)
  - Passbook for savings account, 1943-1957 (Box 251:, Folder 5511)
  - Popular Science Plaque, 1941 October 15 (Box 251:, Folder 5512)
  - New England Wildflower Preservation Society medal, undated (Box 251:, Folder 5513)
  - Christopher medal, 1957 Feb.25 (Box 251:, Folder 5514)
  - "Gramps" Gold Watch- see Dune Boy, undated (Box 251:, Folder 5515)
  - Sarah Joseph Hale Award, undated (Box 251:, Folder 5516)
  - Garden Club of America medal, undated (Box 251:, Folder 5517)
  - John Burrough's Medal, undated (Box 251:, Folder 5518)
  - Glasses in case (no lens), undated (Box 251:, Folder 5519)
  - Grammar school & high school related memorabilia, undated (Box 252:, Folder 5520)
  - Program from EWT's high school graduation, 1918 June 16 - 19 (Box 252:, Folder 5521)
  - EWT's discharge papers (from Army), 1918 December 21 (Box 252:, Folder 5522)
  - College related memorabilia, ca. 1922 (Box 252:, Folder 5523)
  - Engagement announcement, Wedding announcement, EWT's Popular Science business card, program from play, invitation to banquet, EWT's biographical data, 1921-1930 (Box 252:, Folder 5524)
  - Earlham College & Friend's University memorabilia, 1919-1924 (Box 252:, Folder 5525)
  - EWT's Biographical notes, undated (Box 252:, Folder 5526)
  - Miscellaneous Promotional literature for EWT, ca. 1940s (Box 252:, Folder 5527)
  - The Blue Book of Awards- proof of Teale's biographical data, 1943 (Box 252:, Folder 5528)
  - Edwin & Nellie's Motor Vehicle registration certificate, 1927 (Box 252:, Folder 5529)
  - Teale's Christmas card proofs, 1970's (Box 252:, Folder 5530)
  - Blank letterhead, undated (Box 252:, Folder 5531)
  - Post cards- mostly from trips, undated (Box 252:, Folder 5532)
  - Ideas for photo shops, undated (Box 252:, Folder 5533)
  - Brochures of EWT's exhibit at the Charles W. Bowers Memorial Museum, 1961 October (Box 252:, Folder 5534)
  - Edwin's & Nellie's passports used for Springtime in Britain trip, 1966 (Box 252:, Folder 5535)
  - Edwin & Nellie's notes on house hunting, undated (Box 252:, Folder 5536)
  - Old Deed to "Trail Wood" from previous owner, 1801 December (Box 252:, Folder 5537)
  - Notebook & notes on inventory of Trail Wood, 1965 (Box 252:, Folder 5538)
  - Audubon Society agreement for ownership of Trail Wood, 1980 December 30 (Box 252:, Folder 5539)
  - Edwin & Nellie's wills and correspondence relating to, 1961 (Box 252:, Folder 5540)
  - Record book of quotations used in EWT's books, undated (Box 253:, Folder 5541)
  - Cards with EWT and NDT's signatures on them, undated (Box 253:, Folder 5542)
  - EWT's comments on Nellie, undated (Box 253:, Folder 5543)
  - Head Stone related documents for NDT and EWT, 1980 (Box 253:, Folder 5544)
  - Library of Congress Correspondence re: donation of Teale material, 1964-1980 (Box 253:, Folder 5545)
  - Estate related documents & letters, undated (Box 253:, Folder 5546)
  - Earlham College Yearbook, 1916 (Box 254:, Folder 5547)
  - Earlham College Yearbook, 1919 (Box 254:, Folder 5548)
  - Earlham College Yearbook, 1921 (Box 254:, Folder 5549)
  - Earlham College Yearbook, 1922 (Box 254:, Folder 5550)
  - Friends University Yearbook, 1924 (Box 254:, Folder 5551)
  - Joliet Township High School Yearbook, 1918 (Box 254:, Folder 5552)
  - Trail Wood- Name ideas and plans for workroom, undated (Box 255:, Folder 5553)
  - Trail Wood- Guest Book, 1959-1976 (Box 255:, Folder 5554)
  - Trail Wood list of visitors, 1976 (Box 255:, Folder 5555)
  - Trail Wood Guest Book, 1976-1984 (Box 255:, Folder 5556)
  - Trail Wood Guest Book- the Dedication of Trail Wood, 1981 May 17 (Box 255:, Folder 5557)
  - Trail Wood Flyers & Brochures, 1980-1990s (Box 255:, Folder 5557B)
  - EWT's & NDT's Address books, undated (Box 255:, Folder 5558)
  - EWT's & NDT's Address books, undated (Box 255:, Folder 5559)
  - Academic hoods, undated; (2) (Box 256)
  - Oversize Memorabilia / Art Work / Awards
    - University of Connecticut Teale Exhibit Posters, 1981 August - October (Box 257:, Folder 5560)
    - Art Work- Mixed Media by H. N. Bagley "Nature's Art Float-a-Graph", 1946 (Box 257:, Folder 5561)
    - Popular Science Posters (4 Covers from Magazines), ca. 1930s (Box 257:, Folder 5562)
    - Art Work- Printed Boards w/ pictures of Allan Cruickshank, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5563)
    - Art Work- Caption/ Description of painting displayed at reference desk, 1962 (Box 257:, Folder 5564)
    - Copy of Photograph of Walden Pond- sent by Inez Haring, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5565)
    - Award: from The Royal Photographic Society of Great Britain, 1949 November 14 (Box 257:, Folder 5566)
    - Certificate: Kentucky Historical Society, 1967 January (Box 257:, Folder 5567)
    - EWT's Massachusetts Horticultural Society Award, 1975 March 19 (Box 257:, Folder 5568)
    - Nellie's Bird Notes: Drawing of Bird Sightings, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5569)
    - Acrylic Painting by Charles Ripper, 1974 (Box 257:, Folder 5570)
    - Art Work: signed by Guy J. Coheleac sent to EWT by artist, 1967 (Box 257:, Folder 5571)
    - Art Work: Pen & Ink drawing by Carol Snow given to Teale's from Ann Zwinger, 1977 October 24 (Box 257:, Folder 5572)
    - Art Work: Mixed Media- Picture of Connie Hagar's dog "Trixie", 1949 (Box 257:, Folder 5573)
    - Art Work: Watercolor & Charcoal by Lester M. Chace, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5574)
    - Art Work: 6 Prints of Birds by Francis Lee Jaques, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5575)
    - Art Work: 9 Prints of Birds by Roger Tory Peterson, 1958 (Box 257:, Folder 5576)
    - Art Work: Print of Geese by Peter Scott, 1954 (Box 257:, Folder 5577)
    - Art Work: Pen & Ink & Watercolor by Seiel, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5578)
    - Art Work: Mixed Media by Chick Kane, 1946 (Box 257:, Folder 5579)
    - 2 Matted Photographs by Lynn Smith "Cheshire Cat", "Natural Camouflage", 1979 Aug. (Box 257:, Folder 5580)
    - Photographs by Laurence J. Vertefeuille, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5581)
    - Photograph by Lester M. Chace, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5582)
    - Charcoal & Colored Pencil Illustration- by David Teale?, ca. 1930 (Box 257:, Folder 5583)
    - Art Work: Scratchboard illustration by M. H. Bevans, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5584)
    - Art Work: Scratchboard illustration by M. H. Bevans, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5585)
    - Art Work: Scratchboard illustration by M. H. Bevans, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5586)
    - Art Work: Scratchboard illustration by M. H. Bevans, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5587)
    - Art Work: Scratchboard illustration by M. H. Bevans, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5588)
    - Watercolor Illustration by Lester M. Chace, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5589)
    - Pen & Ink Illustration by Florence Jacques, undated (Box 257:, Folder 5590)
    - Woodland Portraits- by Jeannette Klute- box of prints, undated
  - Oversize Art Work (Art Storage)
    - Painting by Elsa Godfrey presented to Teales, 1966
    - Portrait of John Burroughs by Chas F. Lummis, 1921
    - Print of Earlham Hall, Earlham College, undated
    - Oil Painting of a man camping at night by Paul Lentz- illustration from The Lost Dog, undated
    - Oil Painting of a dog in a field by Paul Lentz- illustration from The Lost Dog, undated
    - Oil Painting of an airplane flying over mountain range by Paul Lentz- illustration from The Lost Dog, undated
    - 4 Matted photographs taken by Teale, undated (Box 257B:, Folder 5590B)
  - Awards- EWT
    - Certificate: The Association of Interpretive Naturalists, undated (Box 258:, Folder 5591)
    - Northwestern University Alumni Association for Criminal Research Certificate, 1931 May 9 (Box 258:, Folder 5592)
    - National Geographic Society Certificate, 1937 September 3 (Box 258:, Folder 5593)
    - Certificate: The Council of the American Geographical Society, 1946 January 24 (Box 258:, Folder 5594)
    - Certificate: The American Ornithologist's Union, 1946 September (Box 258:, Folder 5595)
    - Certificate: The New York Academy of Sciences, 1949 (Box 258:, Folder 5596)
    - Earlham Alumni Citation Award, 1952 October (Box 258:, Folder 5597)
    - Baldwin Chamber of Commerce Certificate, 1954 March 31 (Box 258:, Folder 5598)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science Awards, 1954 June (Box 258:, Folder 5599)
    - National Geographic Society Certificate, 1956 June 19 (Box 258:, Folder 5600)
    - Earlham College, Doctor of Letters Honorary Degree notes, program, Merrill Root's speech, correspondence, 1957 June 8 - 9 (Box 258:, Folder 5601)
    - Earlham College, Doctor of Letters Honorary Degree, 1957 June 9 (Box 258:, Folder 5602)
    - Secondary Education Board Annual Book Certificate, 1961 March 3 (Box 258:, Folder 5603)
    - Indiana University Writer's Conference Award, 1961 April 16 (Box 258:, Folder 5604)
    - The Carey-Thomas Award for Creative publishing, 1965 (Box 258:, Folder 5605)
    - University of New Haven, Doctor of Science Degree, 1978 June 4 (Box 258:, Folder 5606)
  - Finances
    - Expense book, undated (Box 259:, Folder 5607)
    - Edwin & Nellie's expense books, 1950-1958; (2) (Box 259:, Folder 5608)
    - Edwin & Nellie's expense book, 1976-1980 (Box 259:, Folder 5609)
    - Expense books- "Journey to England", 1966-1970 (Box 259:, Folder 5610)
    - Finance Notes, undated (Box 259:, Folder 5611)
    - Finances- notebook on sales of books, undated (Box 259:, Folder 5612)
    - Royalty Statements- Miscellaneous Companies, undated (Box 259:, Folder 5613)
    - Royalty Statements- Dodd Mead & Co., undated (Box 259:, Folder 5614-5615)
    - Royalty Statements- E. P. Dutton, undated (Box 259:, Folder 5616-5617)
    - Royalty Statements- Houghton Mifflin & Co., undated (Box 259:, Folder 5618)
    - Royalty Statements- Viking Press, undated (Box 259:, Folder 5619)
- Series XI: Other Author's Manuscript Material Given to EWT & NDT, undated, 1951-1991
  - The Birds of Edwin Way Teale - forward by Helen Cruickshank and note from Parker Huber, 1984 March 17 (Box 260:, Folder 5620)
  - Invisible as the Wind-the Biography of EWT by Robert Holland manuscript, undated (Box 260:, Folder 5621)
  - "He Found Fame in His Backyard" by Roul Tunley, manuscript correspondence, notes, 1964 (Box 260:, Folder 5622)
  - "An Analysis of the Use of Metaphors and Similes by Naturalist Writer Edwin Way Teale," by Millard C. Davis, manuscript, undated (Box 260:, Folder 5623)
  - "Teale's Way" by Millard C. Davis, draft, 1973 (Box 260:, Folder 5624)
  - "The Bridge at Trail Wood" by Millard C. Davis, manuscript, ca. 1984 (Box 260:, Folder 5625)
  - "Gods in Nature" by Millard C. Davis, manuscript, ca. 1984 (Box 260:, Folder 5626)
  - "A Time to Recall" by Millard C. Davis, manuscript and inscription to Nellie, 1984 November 28 (Box 260:, Folder 5627)
  - Incomplete manuscript by Millard C. Davis and note to Nellie, 1985 April 8 (Box 260:, Folder 5628)
  - "The Vegetation and Wildlife of the Edwin Way Teale Sanctuary" by Frank Egler and Jeffrey Davis, manuscript and correspondence, 1982 (Box 260:, Folder 5629)
  - "Nature at Its Finest: The Edwin Way Teale Collection" by John P. McDonald, first draft, 1987 July (Box 260:, Folder 5630)
  - "Nature at Its Finest: The Edwin Way Teale Collection" by John P. McDonald, final draft, 1987 August 17 (Box 260:, Folder 5631)
  - Proposal for the study of EWT's work, from Peggy Moran, 1986 (Box 260:, Folder 5632)
  - "Edwin Way Teale: Here and There, Then and Now" by Thomas A. Potter, copy of speech and poster, 1991 November 10 (Box 260:, Folder 5632B)
  - Walter Harding and Edwin Way Teale by J. Parker Huber, manuscript notes with comments and final publication, 1983 (Box 260:, Folder 5633)
  - Short Stories by Louis B. Chace - manuscripts, ca. 1965 (Box 260:, Folder 5634)
  - Poem: "Pines That Dream Forever" by Louis B. Chace, 1954 (Box 260:, Folder 5635)
  - "Sunday River" poem written for EWT by F. Higginso Swage, 1967 (Box 260:, Folder 5636)
  - "Benjamin Jones and his Garden" poem by Aileen Fisher, ca. 1951 (Box 260:, Folder 5637)
  - "Butterflies in the Rain" poem by Erell Reaves, undated (Box 260:, Folder 5638)